Music
音乐
With your support, this evening's music will benefit the Wildlife Conservation Society.
在您的支持下，今晚的音乐会将有助于野生动物保护协会。
For a hundred years, the remarkable men and women of this great American institution have been fighting to save wildlife and wild places for future generations.
一百年来，这个伟大的美国机构的杰出男女一直在为将来的世代拯救野生动植物和自然环境而努力。
That's why I'm a member.
这就是为什么我是会员。
Join me. Together, we can make a world of difference.
加入我。一起，我们可以改变世界。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Sound of wind
风声
Music
音乐
Applause
掌声
Music
音乐
Horses of creatures who worship the earth
崇拜大地的生物之马
They gallop on feet of ivory
它们奔跑在象牙的脚上
Constrained by the wonders of dying and birth
受到死亡和诞生奇迹的限制
The horses still run, they are free
马仍然奔跑，它们是自由的
My body is merely the shell of my soul
我的身体只是灵魂的外壳
But the flesh must be given it's due
但肉体必须得到它的尊重
Like a pony that carries its rider back home
像一匹扛着骑手回家的小马
Like an old friend who's tried and been true
像一个曾经经受考验且忠诚的老朋友
I had a vision of eagles and horses
我看到了鹰和马的幻象
High on a ridge and a race through the wind
高高在岭上，与风竞赛
Going higher and higher, faster and faster
越来越高，越来越快
On eagles and horses, come July again
在鹰和马之间，七月又来临
Music
音乐
Eagles and habit, the heavenly heights
鹰和习惯，天堂的高度
They know neither limits nor bounds
它们不知道极限或界限
They're the guardian angels of darkness and light
它们是黑暗与光明的守护天使
They see all and hear every sound
它们看到一切，听到每一个声音
My spirit will never be broken nor caught
我的精神永远不会被打破或被困住
All the souls of free-flying things
所有自由飞翔生物的灵魂
Like an eagle that needs neither comfort nor a pie
像一只鹰，不需要安慰或派
To rise upon glorious wings
以光荣的翅膀升腾
I had a vision of eagles and horses
我看到了鹰和马的幻象
High on a ridge and a race through the wind
高高在岭上，与风竞赛
Going higher and higher, faster and faster
越来越高，越来越快
On eagles and horses, I'm flying again
在鹰和马之间，我再次飞翔
I'm flying again
我再次飞翔
Music
音乐
My body is merely the shell of my soul
我的身体只是灵魂的外壳
But the flesh must be given it's due
但肉体必须得到它的尊重
Like a pony that carries its master back home
像一匹扛着骑手回家的小马
Like an old friend who's tried and been true
像一个曾经经受考验且忠诚的老朋友
Music
音乐
My spirit will never be broken nor caught
我的精神永远不会被打破或被困住
All the souls of free-flying things
所有自由飞翔生物的灵魂
Like an eagle that needs neither comfort nor a pie
像一只鹰，不需要安慰或派
To rise upon glorious wings
以光荣的翅膀升腾
I had a vision of eagles and horses
我看到了鹰和马的幻象
High on a ridge and a race through the wind
高高在岭上，与风竞赛
Going higher and higher, faster and faster
越来越高，越来越快
On eagles and horses, I'm flying again
在鹰和马之间，我再次飞翔
I'm flying again
我再次飞翔
Music
音乐
Almost heaven West Virginia
几乎是天堂，西弗吉尼亚
Blue Ridge Mountain, Shenandoah River
蓝岭山，仙纳多河
Life is older than the trees
生命比树木更古老
Younger than the mountains
比山脉更年轻
Growing like the breeze
生长如微风
Country roads take me home
乡村小路带我回家
To the place I belong
到我属于的地方
West Virginia
西弗吉尼亚
Mountain, my mind, take me home
山脉，我的思绪，带我回家
Country roads
乡村小路
All my memories
所有我的回忆
Together around her
围绕在她周围
I'm waiting stranger to the world
我等待着陌生的世界
Dark and dusty, painted on the sky
黑暗而尘土飞扬，绘在天空上
Misty taste of moonshine
淡淡的月光味道
Teardrops in my eyes
眼中的泪滴
Country roads take me home
乡村小路带我回家
To the place I belong
到我属于的地方
West Virginia
西弗吉尼亚
Mountain, my mind, take me home
山脉，我的思绪，带我回家
Country roads
乡村小路
I hear her voice in the morning hour
我在早晨听到她的声音
She calls me
她呼唤我
Radio reminds me of my home
收音机让我想起我的家乡
Far away
遥远的地方
Driving down the road
驾车在路上
I get a feeling that I should have been home
我有一种感觉，我应该回家
Yesterday
昨天
Country roads
乡村小路
Take me home
带我回家
To the place I belong
到我属于的地方
West Virginia
西弗吉尼亚
Mountain, my mind, take me home
山脉，我的思绪，带我回家
Country roads
乡村小路
I want to hear you now
我想现在听到你
Country roads
乡村小路
Take me home
带我回家
To the place I belong
到我属于的地方
West Virginia
西弗吉尼亚
Mountain, my mind, take me home
山脉，我的思绪，带我回家
Country roads
乡村小路
Take me home
带我回家
That country roads
那乡村小路
Take me home
带我回家
That country roads
那乡村小路
There's a storm across the clouds
云层上方有一场风暴
Clouds are cold again
云层再次寒冷
The afternoon is heavy
下午很沉重
On your shoulder
在你的肩上
There's a truck out on the forer lane
有一辆卡车在前方车道
A mile or four away
大约一英里或四英里远
And the winding of his wheels
车轮的声音
Just makes it colder
只是让天气更冷
He's an hour away from riding
他距离家还有一个小时的路程
On your prayers up in the sky
在你的祈祷中
Ten days on the road
在路上十天
Barely gone again
几乎又离开
There's a fire softly burning
那里有一团温暖的火
Suppers on the stove
晚餐正在炉上烹制
There's a light in your eyes
在你的眼中有一抹光
That makes him warm in the city
让他在城市感到温暖
It's good to be back home again
回到家真好
Sometimes it's so far
有时候好远
Feels like a long lost friend
感觉像是一个久违的朋友
Yes, it's good to be back home again
是的，回家真好
Back home again
再次回家
There's all the news to tell you
有很多新闻要告诉你
Honey, how do you spend your time?
亲爱的，你是如何度过时间的？
Tell me what's the latest thing
告诉我最新的事情
The neighbors say
邻居们都在说
And your mother called last Friday
你妈妈上周五打来电话
The sunshine did her crime
阳光使她开心
And you felt the baby root
你感觉到宝宝的成长
Just yesterday
就在昨天
It's good to be back home again
回到家真好
Yes, it's good
是的，回家真好
Sometimes it's so far
有时候好远
Feels like a long lost friend
感觉像是一个久违的朋友
Yes, it's good to be back home again
是的，回家真好
All the time that I can't wait
一直等待的时光
It's tired, old body now
现在是疲惫的老身体
Feel your fingers feather-sunk
感受你的手指轻抚
The kiss says that I live for
吻告诉我我为之生活
The love that I'd swear to death
我发誓爱到死
Happiness, the living with you brings me
幸福，与你生活在一起给我带来的
It's the sweetest thing I know of
这是我所知道的最甜蜜的事情
Just been in time with you
就是与你共度时光
It's the little things that make a house a home
就是一些小事让房子成为家
Like a fire softly burning
比如轻轻燃烧的火
And suffer on the stove
和炉子上的晚餐
And the light in your eyes
以及你眼中的光
It keeps me warm
它让我感到温暖
You sing it once
你再唱一次
It's good to be back home again
回到家真好
All the time that I can't wait
一直等待的时光
Sometimes it's so far
有时候好远
Feels like a long lost friend
感觉像是一个久违的朋友
Yes, it's good to be back home again
是的，回家真好
All the time that I can't wait
一直等待的时光
It's good to be back home again
回到家真好
You know it is
你知道的
Sometimes it's so far
有时候好远
Feels like a long lost friend
感觉像是一个久违的朋友
It's good to be back home again
回到家真好
I said hey, it's so good to be back home again
我说，嘿，回家真好
The Wildlife Conservation Society is one of the largest environmental organizations
野生生物保护协会是最大的环保组织之一
And I think the one doing the most hands-on work
我认为它正在进行最多的实地工作
Everywhere around the world
遍布世界各地
You think about wildlife, you think of just animals
一提到野生动物，你只会想到动物
And you don't think about habitat
你不会考虑栖息地
You don't think about where they live, how they live
你不会想到它们生活的地方，它们如何生活
The foods they eat, the ecosystem
它们的食物，生态系统
That is a part of their existence
那是它们生存的一部分
And for so many, for so much of what wildlife is about
对于许多人和许多野生动物而言
What wilderness is about has to do with these larger issues
野外之美与这些更广泛的问题有关
And not all organizations are as deeply or as broadly involved
并不是所有组织都如此深入或广泛地参与
As the Wildlife Conservation Society in these areas
就像野生生物保护协会在这些领域一样
And you say that the battle is over
你说战斗已经结束
Finally the war is all done
终于，战争已经结束
Go tell it to those with the wind in their nose
去告诉那些面临威胁的动物
Who run from the sound of the gun
它们从枪声中逃跑
And ride it on the sides of the great whaling ships
在座右铭于捕鲸船的侧面
For on ice floes where conscience is tossed
在冰块上，良知被抛弃
With the wild in their eyes it is they who must die
在它们的眼中充满野性，它们却必须死去
We who must measure the loss
我们必须衡量损失
And you say that the battle is over
你说战斗已经结束
Finally the world is at peace
终于，世界和平了
You mean no one is dying and mothers don't weep
你的意思是没有人再死去，母亲不再哭泣
Or it's not in the papers at least
或者至少没有出现在报纸上
There are those who would deal in the darkness of life
有些人选择在黑暗中谋生
There are those who would tear down the sun
有些人试图摧毁太阳
And most men are ruthless but some will still weep
大多数人是无情的，但有些人仍然会哭泣
When the gifts we were given are gone
当我们所赋予的礼物消失时
Oh the blame cannot rest on the heads of the few
哦，责任不能只归咎于少数人
It's become such a part of the race
它已经成为了竞赛的一部分
It's eternally tragic that which is magic
这永恒的悲剧与神奇相伴
Be killed at the end of the glorious chase
在辉煌的追逐之后被杀死
From young seals to great whales, from waters to wood
从年幼的海豹到庞大的鲸鱼，从水域到森林
They will fall just like weeds in the wind
它们将像风中的野草一样倒下
With perfume and fur coats and trophies on walls
带着香水、毛皮外套和墙上的奖杯
What a hell of a race to call men
真是一场可怕的比赛，竟然叫人类
And you say that the battle is over
你说战斗已经结束
Finally the war is all done
终于战争结束了
Go tell it to those with the wind in their nose
去告诉那些闻到危险的动物
Who run from the sound of the gun
它们从枪声中逃跑
And ride it on the sides of the great whaling ships
它们被用来挂在捕鲸船的侧面
For on ice floes where conscience is tossed
在冰块上，良知被抛弃
With the wild in their eyes it is they who must die
它们眼中充满野性，它们必须死去
We who must measure the loss
我们必须衡量损失
With the wild in their eyes it is they who must die
眼中充满野性，它们必须死去
And we who will measure the cost
而我们将衡量代价
We will be dead
我们将死去
I have a woman friend whose name is Marty Murie
我有一个女性朋友，她的名字叫Marty Murie
And she's 93 years old
她已经93岁了
And I think she has done more for Alaska
我认为她为阿拉斯加做的事情比任何其他人都多
Than any other single human being
比其他任何一个人都多
And it comes out of not only her love
而且这不仅仅源于她的爱
And the experience that she had in that great land
还有她在那片伟大土地上的经历
And her love for that land
以及她对那片土地的热爱
But her love for the man who was her husband
还有她对她丈夫的爱
Whose name is Olas Murie
他叫Olas Murie
And when Olas passed away many, many years ago
而当Olas多年前去世时
The way that Marty kept his love and her feeling for him
Marty保持着对他的爱和对他的感情的方式
Alive in her heart was to commit herself
就是承诺自己
To saving the land that they both loved
去拯救他们共同热爱的土地
So very, very much
如此之多
I know a lot of things I could tell you about Marty
我知道很多关于Marty的事情可以告诉你
But the thing that I want to share with you is that
但我想和你分享的是
She spoke of Olas always as her beloved
她总是称Olas为她的至爱
And they love to dance, the waltz especially
他们喜欢跳舞，尤其是华尔兹
And they danced whenever they could
他们随时跳舞
Whenever they felt like it regardless of the conditions
不管条件如何，只要他们想跳
And I have this picture of them
我心中有一幅他们的画面
Out in the frozen tundra of Alaska
在冰封的阿拉斯加荒原上
In each other's arms dancing
在彼此的怀抱中跳舞
And no music except the sound of the wind
除了风声，没有音乐
Rushing across that frozen wasteland
穿越那片冰冻荒地
Or some place in a forest or some place beneath the full moon
或者在森林中的某个地方，或者在满月下的某个地方
And so I wrote this song for Marty
所以我为Marty写了这首歌
I see them dancing
我看见他们在跳舞
Somewhere in the moonlight
在月光下的某个地方
Somewhere in Alaska
在阿拉斯加的某个地方
Somewhere in the sun
在阳光下的某个地方
I hear them singing
我听到他们在唱歌
A song for all lovers
一首给所有恋人的歌
A song for the two hearts
一首给两颗心的歌
Meeting only as one
只会作为一个相遇
Imagine the morning
想象着早晨
No longer alone
不再孤单
The arms of another
另一个的臂膀
A place to belong
一个属于自己的地方
No longer the struggle
不再斗争
No longer the night
不再黑夜
And ever becoming
变得更加美好
In the quickening light
在快速变亮的光芒中
To see in the darkness
在黑暗中看到
To listen within
倾听内心
To answer in kindness
以善意回应
To ever begin
不断开始
To ever be gentle
永远温柔
To always be strong
始终坚强
To walk in the wonder
在奇迹中行走
To live in the song
活在歌声中
In a place of enchantment
在一个充满魔力的地方
Where the wild things are known
那里已知野生生物
Will the future remember
未来会记住
When the lovers are gone
当恋人们离去
To ever be gentle
永远温柔
To always be strong
始终坚强
To walk in the wonder
在奇迹中行走
To live in the song
活在歌声中
And I see them dancing
我看见他们在跳舞
Somewhere in the moonlight
在月光下的某个地方
Somewhere in Alaska
在阿拉斯加的某个地方
Somewhere in the sun
在阳光下的某个地方
I hear them singing
我听到他们在唱歌
A song for all lovers
一首给所有恋人的歌
A song for the two hearts
一首给两颗心的歌
Meeting only as one
只会作为一个相遇
A song for the two hearts
一首给两颗心的歌
Meeting only as one
只会作为一个相遇
Thank you
谢谢
He was born in the son of his 27th year
他出生在他的第27年
Coming home to a place he'd never been for
回到一个他从未去过的地方
Left yesterday behind him
昨天已经留在身后
You might say he was born again
你可以说他重生了
You might say he found a key for every door
你可以说他找到了打开每扇门的钥匙
When he first came to the mountains
当他第一次来到这座山
His life was far away on the road
他的生活远离了道路
Hanging by a song
依赖一首歌
But the train has already broken
但列车已经坏了
And then he doesn't really care
然后他并不真的在乎
Keep changing fast
快速改变
It don't last long
它不会持续很久
Colorado, Rocky Mountain High
科罗拉多，落基山高
I've seen it rain in the fire and the sky
我曾见过火中和天空下雨
The shadow from the starlight
星光下的阴影
Is softening a little goodbye
正在柔化着一次小小的告别
Rocky Mountain High
落基山高
He climbed Cathedral mountains
他攀登着大教堂山
Saw silver clouds below
看到下面的银色云彩
Saw everything as far as you can see
看到远方的一切
And he said that he got crazy
他说他疯了
Once he tried to touch the sun
他曾试图触摸太阳
And he lost a friend but kept his memory
他失去了一个朋友，但保留了他的记忆
Now he walks in quiet solitude
现在他在宁静的孤独中行走
The forest on the street
在林中漫游
Taking grace in every step he takes
每一步都充满了宠爱
His side has turned inside himself
他的内心已经转向自己
To try and understand
试图理解
The serenity of the blue-blue mouth play
蓝天的宁静
Colorado, Rocky Mountain High
科罗拉多，落基山高
I've seen it rain in the fire and the sky
我曾见过火中和天空下雨
You can talk to God and listen to the casual reply
你可以与上帝交谈并聆听随意的回答
Rocky Mountain High
落基山高
Now his life is full of wonder
现在他的生活充满了奇迹
But his heart still knows some fear
但他的心仍然知道一些恐惧
Of the simple thing he cannot comprehend
他无法理解的简单事物
While they try to tear the muffins down
当他们试图摧毁面包时
To bring in a couple more
引进更多
More people, more scars upon the land
更多的人，更多的伤痕
Colorado, Rocky Mountain High
科罗拉多，落基山高
I've seen it rain in the fire and the sky
我曾见过火中和天空下雨
I know he'd be a poor man
我知道他会成为一个贫穷的人
If he never saw an eagle fly
如果他从未看到老鹰飞翔
Rocky Mountain High
落基山高
It's a Colorado, Rocky Mountain High
这是科罗拉多，落基山高
I've seen it rain in the fire and the sky
我曾见过火中和天空下雨
It's a Colorado, can't fire
这是科罗拉多，无法燃烧
Everybody's high
每个人都高兴
Rocky Mountain High
落基山高
For me me
对我来说
Iron Man
铁人
I guess he'd rather be in Colorado
我想他宁愿在科罗拉多
He'd rather spend his time out where the sky looks like a bird after rain
他宁愿在天空中度过时间，就像雨后的鸟一样
Once again I see him walking, once again I hear him talking
再次我看到他在走路，再次我听到他在谈话
To the stars he makes, and asking them for less bed
他向星星祈祷，请求得到更少的床
I guess he'd rather be in Colorado
我想他宁愿在科罗拉多
He'd rather play his banjo in the morning when the moon is scarcely gone
他更愿意在早晨弹奏班卓琴，当月亮刚刚落下
In the dawn the subway's coming, in the dawn I hear him humming
黎明时分，地铁即将到来，在黎明时分我听到他哼唱
Some old song he wrote of love and bolder canyon
一首他创作的关于爱情和大胆峡谷的老歌
I guess he'd rather be in Colorado
我想他宁愿在科罗拉多
I guess he'd rather work out where the only thing you earn is what you spend
我想他宁愿工作，只有你花费的才是你赚取的东西
In the end of his office, in the end of quiet calls
最后，在他的办公室，安静的电话结束
Is all he has to show, he lives in New York City
这就是他展示的一切，他生活在纽约市
I guess he'd rather be in Colorado
我想他宁愿在科罗拉多
It's not that I'm uncomfortable in cities, it's just that I'm more comfortable and more at home and more at peace with myself
并不是我不喜欢城市，只是我在自己更加自在和舒适，更加和平
Outside of all of this chaos, at the time that I first heard I guess he'd rather be in Colorado
远离这一切混乱，在我第一次听到的时候，我想他宁愿在科罗拉多
I was getting to a place in my life where more and more I yearned to live someplace in the west, someplace in the mountains
我正处于人生中渴望生活在西部的地方的阶段，某处在山区
Just when the way last summer, a couple of months ago
就在上个夏天的时候，大约几个月前
After all our time together, it was hard to see her go
经历了我们在一起的时光，很难看到她离去
She called me right up when she arrived, asked me one more time to come
她一到达就给我打电话，再次邀请我前来
But living on an LA freeway ain't my kind of heaven for
但在洛杉矶的高速公路上生活不是我向往的天堂
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我宁愿成为一个牛仔
I think I'd rather ride the rain
我想我宁愿骑在雨中
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我宁愿成为一个牛仔
Then lay me down in love with ladies' chains
而不是让我陷入对女人的爱的束缚
We were just beginning, it was such an easy way
我们刚刚开始，那是如此容易的方式
Laying back up in the mountains, making love for sunny days
躺在山上，享受阳光明媚的日子，享受爱情
She got tired of picking daisies, they're cooking my meals for me
她厌倦了摘雏菊，她给我做饭
She can live the life she wants to, yes, it's alright with me
她可以过她想要的生活，是的，对我来说没问题
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我宁愿成为一个牛仔
I think I'd rather ride the rain
我想我宁愿骑在雨中
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我宁愿成为一个牛仔
Then lay me down in love with ladies' chains
而不是让我陷入对女人的爱的束缚
I'd rather live on the side of a mountain
我宁愿生活在山的一边
And wander through canyons of concrete and steel
在混凝土和钢铁的峡谷中漫步
I'd rather live with the rain and the sunshine
我宁愿和雨水和阳光生活在一起
And lay down my son down in somethings I reveal
并坚持我的孩子躺在我展示的东西中
I miss her in the morning when I awake alone
当我独自醒来时，我想念她的早晨
The absence of her laughter is a cold and empty sound
她笑声的缺席是一种冷冽而空虚的声音
Her memory always makes me smile and I want you to know
她的回忆总是让我微笑，我想让你知道
I love her, yes I love her, just enough to let her go
我爱她，是的，我爱她，足够让她离去
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我宁愿成为一个牛仔
I think I'd rather ride the rain
我想我宁愿骑在雨中
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我宁愿成为一个牛仔
Then lay me down in love with ladies' chains
而不是让我陷入对女人的爱的束缚
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我宁愿成为一个牛仔
I think I'd rather ride the rain
我想我宁愿骑在雨中
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我宁愿成为一个牛仔
Then lay me down in love with ladies' chains
而不是让我陷入对女人的爱的束缚
Just a look in your eyes again, just to lay in your arms
再次看着你的眼睛，只是躺在你的怀抱中
Just to be the first one, always there for you
只是想成为第一个，永远在你身边
Just to live in your laughter, just to sing in your heart
只是生活在你的笑声中，只是在你的心中歌唱
Just to be every one of your dreams come true
只是成为你的每一个梦想成真
Just to sit by your window, just to touch in the night
只是坐在你的窗前，只是在夜晚触摸
Just to offer a prayer each day for you
只是每天为你祈祷
Just to long for your kisses, just to dream of your sighs
只是渴望你的吻，只是梦想着你的叹息
Just to know that I'd give my life to you
只是知道我会为你付出我的生命
For you, for the rest of my life, for you, for the best of my life
为你，为我的余生，为你，为我最美好的时光
For you, love, only for you
为你，只为你
Just to wake up each morning, just to you by my side
只是每天早上醒来，只是你在我身边
Just to know that you're never really far away
只要知道你其实从未离得很远
Just a reason for living, just to say I adore you
只是一个活着的理由，只是为了说我崇拜你
Just to know that you're here in my heart to stay
只要知道你在我的心中停留
For you, for the rest of my life, for you, for the best of my life
为你，为我的余生，为你，为我最美好的时光
For you, love
为你，爱
Just a reason only for you
只为你的一个理由
Just a words of a love song
只是一首情歌的歌词
Just a beat of my heart
只是我心跳的节奏
Just a pledge of my life, my life for you
只是我生命的承诺，为你的生命
Just a word of my heart
只是我心中的话语
It's cold here in the city, it always seems that way
城市里很冷，似乎总是这样
I've been thinking about you almost every day
我几乎每天都在想你
Thinking about the good times, thinking about the rain
想着美好的时光，想着雨水
Thinking about how bad it feels alone again
想着再次独自感到多么糟糕
I'm sorry for the way things are in China
我为中国的现状感到抱歉
I'm sorry things ain't what they used to be
我为事物不再是过去的样子感到抱歉
More than anything else, I'm sorry for myself
最重要的是，我为自己感到抱歉
You're not here with me
你不在我身边
Our friends all ask about you
我们的朋友都在问你
I say you're doing fine
我说你过得很好
And I expect to hear from you almost any time
我期待着随时从你那里听到消息
They all know I'm crying, I can't sleep at night
他们都知道我在哭泣，晚上睡不着
They all know I'm dying down deep inside
他们都知道我内心深处正在死去
I'm sorry for all the lies I told you
我为我对你说的谎言感到抱歉
I'm sorry for the things I didn't say
我为我没有说的话感到抱歉
More than anything else, I'm sorry for myself
最重要的是，我为自己感到抱歉
I can't believe you went away
我无法相信你离开了
I'm sorry if I took some things for granted
如果我理所当然地拿走了一些东西，我为此感到抱歉
I'm sorry for the chains I put on you
我为我加在你身上的枷锁感到抱歉
More than anything else, I'm sorry for myself
最重要的是，我为自己感到抱歉
For living without you
因为没有你而生活
I've got a different perspective on a lot of the songs
我对很多歌曲有了不同的看法
It's surprising to me the different levels that I find in a lot of these songs
我发现这些歌曲中有不同的层次，这让我感到惊讶
And how a song I wrote 20 years ago can all of a sudden take on whole new meanings for me
我20年前写的一首歌，突然间对我来说有了全新的意义
And sometimes it happens in the middle of it when you're performing it
有时候，这种感觉会在你表演时突然出现
And all of a sudden you think of something, remember something, or see something that you never did before
突然间，你会想到某件事，记起某件事，或看到以前从未看到的东西
All of her days have gone soft and cloudy
她所有的日子都变得温柔和多云
All of her dreams have gone dry
她所有的梦想都枯竭
All of her nights have gone sad and shady
她所有的夜晚都变得忧郁和阴暗
She's getting ready to fly
她正准备飞翔
Fly away
飞翔
Life in the city can make you crazy
城市生活可能让你发疯
For sounds of the sand and the sea
渴望沙滩和海洋的声音
Life in a high rise can make you hungry
高楼大厦的生活可能让你饥饿
For things that you can't even see
渴望那些你甚至看不见的东西
Fly away
飞翔
In this whole world there's nobody as lonely as she
在这个世界上，没有人像她一样孤独
There's nowhere to go, there's nowhere that she'd rather be
没有地方可去，没有地方比她更想去的地方
She's looking for lovers and children to play in
她正在寻找爱人和孩子来玩耍
She's looking for signs of the spring
她正在寻找春天的迹象
She listens for laughter and sounds of dancing
她聆听着笑声和舞蹈的声音
She listens for any old thing
她聆听着任何旧事
Fly away
飞翔
In this whole world there's nobody as lonely as she
在这个世界上，没有人像她一样孤独
There's nowhere to go, there's nowhere that she'd rather be
没有地方可去，没有地方比她更想去的地方
And all of her days have gone soft and cloudy
她所有的日子都变得温柔和多云
All of her dreams have gone dry
她所有的梦想都枯竭
All of her nights have gone sad and shady
她所有的夜晚都变得忧郁和阴暗
She's getting ready to fly
她正准备飞翔
Fly away
飞翔
They say they love each other
他们说他们相爱
I know that they do
我知道他们是真的相爱
They say they'll always be together
他们说他们将永远在一起
That may not be true
这可能不是真的
They come from different places
他们来自不同的地方
Different points of view
拥有不同的观点
They find themselves in different spaces
他们发现自己处于不同的空间
Everything is all brand new
一切都是崭新的
Too different directions
朝着不同的方向
Too many different ways
太多不同的方式
One always on the road somewhere
一个总是在某个地方旅行
The other one always stays
另一个总是待在原地
Too often unhappy
太经常不开心
Too often on your own
太经常孤单
When you are moving in different directions
当你们朝着不同的方向前进时
True love is all alone
真爱总是孤独的
Old stories start to surface
旧故事开始浮出水面
Patterns from long ago
来自很久以前的模式
And loving quickly turns to anger
爱很快变成了愤怒
For reasons they don't even know
出于他们甚至不知道的原因
The strongest heart can be broken
最坚强的心也可能会破碎
With one insensitive word
仅仅一个无情的词语
The deepest feelings remain unspoken
最深刻的感情仍然未被说出
No one is seen with nothing word
没有人因无言而不被看到
Too different directions
朝向不同的方向
Too many different ways
太多不同的方式
One always wants to work things out
一个总是想解决问题
The other one wants to play
另一个总是想玩耍
Too ready for changes
太愿意改变
And too much that just can't wait
而且有太多东西是无法等待的
When you are moving in different directions
当你们朝着不同的方向前进时
True love can turn to hate
真爱可以变成仇恨
If opposites attract each other
如果相反的事物相互吸引
What's the reason for?
那是因为什么？
One being like an open window
一个像敞开的窗户
One just like a closing door
另一个像是关闭的门
Too different directions
朝向不同的方向
Too many different ways
太多不同的方式
One likes to see the morning sun rise
一个喜欢看到早晨的阳光升起
The other one sleeps in bed
另一个却在床上睡觉
Too many tomorrow
太多的明天
Too many times too late
太多次太晚
When you are moving in different directions
当你们朝着不同的方向前进时
True love may have to wait
真爱也许必须等待
If you are committed to different directions
如果你们致力于不同的方向
True love will have to wait
真爱将不得不等待
Funny how you sound if you're right next door
有趣的是，你听起来就像就在隔壁
When you're really half a world away
当你实际上相隔千里
I just can't seem to find the words I'm looking for
我似乎找不到我要找的词语
To say the things I want to say
说我想说的话
I can't remember when I felt so close to you
我不记得何时我感到如此亲近你
It's almost more than I can bear
这几乎超出了我的承受范围
Though I seem a half a million miles from you
尽管我似乎与你相隔千里
You are in my heart and living there
你在我的心中并且生活在那里
And the moon and the stars are the same
月亮和星星是一样的
What you see is the same old sun up in the sky
你看到的是同样的旧太阳高悬在天空中
Your voice in my ear is like heaven to me
你的声音在我耳边就像天堂一样
Like the breezes here in Old Shanghai
就像上海古老的微风一样
There are lovers who walk hand in hand in the park
有情人手牵手在公园里散步
And lovers who walk all alone
还有一个人孤独地走
There are lovers who lie unafraid in the dark
有情人毫不畏惧地躺在黑暗中
And lovers who long for home
还有一些渴望家的人
I couldn't leave you even if I wanted to
即使我想离开你也不能
You're in my dreams and always dear
你出现在我的梦中，一直亲爱
And especially when I sing the songs I wrote for you
尤其是当我为你唱我写的歌时
You are in my heart and living there
你在我的心中，一直生活在那里
And the moon and the stars are the same
月亮和星星都是相同的
What you see is the same old sun up in the sky
你看到的是同样的太阳升起在天空中
And you're facing my dreams is like heaven to me
你出现在我的梦中，就像天堂一样
Like the breezes here in Old Shanghai
就像上海古老的微风一样
Shanghai breezes cool and clear
上海的微风凉爽而清新
Evening sweet caress
晚上的温柔抚摸
Shanghai breezes soft and gentle
上海的微风柔和而温和
Remind me of your tenderness
让我想起你的温柔
And the moon and the stars are the same
月亮和星星都是相同的
What you see is the same old sun up in the sky
你看到的是同样的太阳升起在天空中
And your love in my life is like heaven to me
而你在我的生活中的爱就像天堂一样
Like the breezes here in Old Shanghai
就像上海古老的微风一样
And the moon and the stars are the same
月亮和星星都是相同的
What you see is the same old sun up in the sky
你看到的是同样的太阳升起在天空中
And your love in my life is like heaven to me
而你在我的生活中的爱就像天堂一样
Like the breezes here in Old Shanghai
就像上海古老的微风一样
Just like the breezes here in Old Shanghai
You fill up my senses like a night in a forest
你填满了我的感官，就像森林中的夜晚
Like the mountains in springtime
就像春日的山峦
Like a walk in the rain
就像在雨中散步
Like a storm in the desert
就像沙漠中的风暴
Like a sleepy blue ocean
就像宁静的蓝色大海
You fill up my senses
你填满了我的感官
Come fill me again
再次来填满我
Come let me love you
来吧，让我爱你
Let me give my life to you
让我把我的生命奉献给你
Let me drown in your laughter
让我沉浸在你的笑声中
Let me die in your arms
让我死在你的怀中
Let me lay down beside you
让我躺在你身旁
Let me always be with you
让我永远与你在一起
Come let me love you
来吧，让我爱你
Come love me again
再次来爱我
Let me give my life to you
让我把我的生命奉献给你
Come let me love you
来吧，让我爱你
Come love me again
再次来爱我
You fill up my senses
你填满了我的感官
Like a night in a forest
就像森林中的夜晚
Like the mountains in springtime
就像春日的山峦
Like a walk in the rain
就像在雨中散步
Like a storm in the desert
就像沙漠中的风暴
Like a sleepy blue ocean
就像宁静的蓝色大海
You fill up my senses
你填满了我的感官
Come fill me again
再次来填满我
My greatest inspiration has always been the Out of Doors.
我的最大灵感一直来自大自然。
The Out of Doors was my first and truest best friend.
大自然是我的第一个，也是最真诚的朋友。
And because of that, when I began to try and express myself,
正因为如此，当我开始尝试表达自己时，
it was a perfectly natural thing for me to use images from nature.
使用来自大自然的图像对我来说是再自然不过的事情。
And my songs are full of images from nature.
我的歌曲充满了大自然的意象。
People may not know West Virginia, but they know what take me home feels like.
人们可能不了解西弗吉尼亚，但他们知道“带我回家”的感觉。
And country roads are, I think, a part of everybody's life.
我认为，乡村小路是每个人生活的一部分。
And those simple things sunshine on my shoulders.
还有那些简单的事情，阳光洒在我的肩上。
In the Annie Song, you fill up my senses like a night in a forest.
在《安妮之歌》中，你填满了我的感官，就像森林中的夜晚。
Like a walk in the rain.
就像在雨中散步。
These are parts of people's experience all over the world.
这些都是世界各地人们的经历的一部分。
Sunshine on my shoulders makes me happy.
阳光洒在我的肩上让我快乐。
Sunshine in my eyes can make me cry.
阳光照在我的眼睛里可以让我哭泣。
Sunshine on the water looks so lovely.
水面上的阳光看起来如此美丽。
Sunshine almost always makes me happy.
阳光几乎总是让我快乐。
If I had a day that I could give you,
如果我有一天可以送给你，
I'd give to you a day just like today.
我会送给你一天，就像今天一样。
If I had a song that I could sing for you,
如果我有一首可以为你唱的歌，
I'd sing a song to make you feel this way.
我会唱一首让你感到快乐的歌。
Sunshine on my shoulders makes me happy.
阳光洒在我的肩上让我快乐。
Sunshine in my eyes can make me cry.
阳光照在我的眼睛里可以让我哭泣。
Sunshine on the water looks so lovely.
水面上的阳光看起来如此美丽。
Sunshine almost always makes me happy.
阳光几乎总是让我快乐。
If I had a tale that I could tell you,
如果我有一个可以告诉你的故事，
I'd tell a tale sure to make you smile.
我会讲一个一定能让你微笑的故事。
If I had a wish that I could wish for you,
如果我有一个可以为你许愿的愿望，
I'd make a wish for sunshine all the while.
我会许愿阳光普照。
Sunshine on my shoulders makes me happy.
阳光洒在我的肩上让我快乐。
Sunshine in my eyes can make me cry.
阳光照在我的眼睛里可以让我哭泣。
Sunshine on the water looks so lovely.
水面上的阳光看起来如此美丽。
Sunshine almost always makes me happy.
阳光几乎总是让我快乐。
When I grew up, the music that my father listened to,
当我长大时，我父亲听的音乐，
the music that I was raised on, was called Country and Western.
我成长的音乐被称为乡村和西部音乐。
And in the years since then, it's gotten to be very much country music.
从那时以来的这些年里，它变得非常乡村音乐。
They took the West out of it.
他们把“西部”从中去掉了。
And although I've been called a country singer,
尽管人们叫我乡村歌手，
and certainly have written some country songs
我当然写过一些乡村歌曲
and had some great success there with things like Country Roads
还在那里取得了一些巨大的成功，比如《乡村小路》
and Back Home Again, Thank God I'm a Country Boy,
和《回家了》，感谢上帝我是个乡村男孩，
I don't feel that I've ever really been accepted by the country artist
我并不认为自己真正被乡村艺术家所接受
or by country music because I'm somehow outside of that.
或是乡村音乐，因为我在某种程度上超越了它。
And I don't really feel like I'm a country artist.
而我并不真的觉得自己是一位乡村艺术家。
I'm more a Western artist.
我更像是一位西部艺术家。
And the songs that are most moving to me
对我来说，最感人的歌曲
and the songs that I think are uniquely mine
我认为是独一无二的
are really not country songs.
实际上不是乡村歌曲。
Notwithstanding the songs that I mentioned,
尽管我提到的歌曲，
songs like Rocky Mountain Highs, that's not a country song.
像《高高的洛矶山》这样的歌曲，那不是乡村歌曲。
Eagles and Horses, that's not a country song.
《鹰与马》也不是乡村歌曲。
Wild Montana Skies, those are songs that come out of the spirit
《狂野蒙大拿天空》，这些歌曲是出自精神
of the American West.
来自美国西部。
It's not that I would much rather represent,
并不是我更愿意代表，
I'd be very proud to be a real part of country music.
我会非常自豪地成为乡村音乐的一部分。
And I love country music, like I say, I was raised on it.
而且我喜欢乡村音乐，就像我说的，我是在其中长大的。
But I like this notion of the American West.
但我喜欢美国西部的概念。
There's nothing in the world like the American West.
世界上没有什么东西可以比得上美国西部。
There's nothing like its people, there's nothing like its splendor,
没有人可以像它的人民那样，没有什么可以像它的壮丽那样，
and there's nothing like its spirit.
没有什么可以比得上它的精神。
And I think the songs that I'm proudest of
我认为我最骄傲的歌曲
are the songs that, to some degree or another,
是那些在某种程度上
express or represent the spirit of the American West.
表达或代表美国西部精神。
In the root valley, near early morning rain,
在根谷，靠近清晨的雨，
while he's over the water, heading north and home again,
当他越过水面，向北回家，
bringing a woman from the south,
带着一位来自南方的女人，
bringing the first taste of the spring.
带来了春天的第一抹滋味。
His mother took him to a breast, softly sheeted, saying,
他的母亲把他抱在怀里，轻声说，
Oh, Montana, give this child a home,
哦，蒙大拿，给这个孩子一个家，
give him the love of a good family,
给他一个温馨的家庭的爱，
and a woman of his own, give him a fire in his heart,
和一个属于他自己的女人，给他一颗火热的心，
give him a light in his eyes,
给他眼中的光明，
give him the wild man for a brother,
给他一个野蛮的兄弟，
and the wild Montana sky.
和蒙大拿的狂野天空。
His mother died at supper, and he never learned to cry.
他的母亲在晚餐时去世，他从未学会哭泣。
He never knew his father, and he never did ask why.
他从未知道他的父亲，也从未问过为什么。
And he never knew the answers, it would make an easy way.
他从未知道答案，这会使一切变得容易。
But he learned to know the wilderness, and to be a man that way.
但他学会了认识荒野，以及以这种方式成为一个男人。
His mother's brother took him into his family and his home,
他的母亲的兄弟把他带到了他的家庭和家里，
gave him a hand, and he could lead all the strength
伸出援手，他可以拥有所有的力量
to call his own.
来指导他自己。
And he learned to be a farmer, and he learned to love the land,
他学会了做农夫，学会了热爱这片土地，
and he learned to read the seasons,
并学会了读懂季节，
and he learned to make a stand.
并学会了坚持立场。
Oh, Montana, give this child a home,
哦，蒙大拿，给这个孩子一个家，
give him the love of a good family,
给他一个温馨的家庭的爱，
and a woman of his own, give him a fire in his heart,
和一个属于他自己的女人，给他一颗火热的心，
give him a light in his eyes,
给他眼中的光明，
give him the wild man for a brother,
给他一个野蛮的兄弟，
and the wild Montana sky.
和蒙大拿的狂野天空。
On the eve of his 21st birthday, he set out on his own.
在他21岁生日前夕，他独自出发。
He was 30 years and running,
他已经30年如一日，
when he found his way back home,
当他找到回家的路，
riding a storm across the mountains,
骑着风暴穿越群山，
and an eight minute park.
和八分钟公园。
Said he came to turn the pages,
他说他来翻动那些页，
and make a brand new start.
开始全新的生活。
Now, when I told the story, the time that he was gone,
现在，当我讲述他离开的故事时，
some say he was a lawyer, some say he was a judge.
有人说他是一名律师，有人说他是一名法官。
There was something in the city that he said he couldn't breathe,
他说在城市里有一些东西让他无法呼吸，
something in the country that he said he couldn't leave.
在乡村也有一些东西，他说他离不开。
Oh, Montana, give this child a home,
哦，蒙大拿，给这个孩子一个家，
give him the love of a good family,
给他一个温馨的家庭的爱，
and a woman of his own, give him a fire in his heart,
和一个属于他自己的女人，给他一颗火热的心，
give him a light in his eyes,
给他眼中的光明，
give him the wild man for a brother,
给他一个野蛮的兄弟，
and the wild Montana sky.
和蒙大拿的狂野天空。
Now, some said he was crazy, some are glad he's gone,
有人说他疯了，有人庆幸他走了，
some of us will miss him, we'll try to carry on,
我们中的一些人会想念他，我们会努力继续，
giving a voice to the forest, giving a voice to the dawn,
为森林和黎明发声，
giving a voice to the wilderness, and the land that we live on.
为荒野和我们生活的土地发声。
Oh, Montana, give this child a home,
哦，蒙大拿，给这个孩子一个家，
give him the love of a good family, and a woman of his own,
给他一个温馨的家庭的爱，和一个属于他自己的女人，
give him a fire in his heart, give him a light in his eyes,
给他一颗火热的心，给他眼中的光明，
give him the wild man for a brother,
给他一个野蛮的兄弟，
and the wild Montana sky.
和蒙大拿的狂野天空。
Oh, Montana, give this child a home,
哦，蒙大拿，给这个孩子一个家，
give him the love of a good family,
给他一个温馨的家庭的爱，
and a woman of his own, give him a fire in his heart,
和一个属于他自己的女人，给他一颗火热的心，
give him a light in his eyes,
给他眼中的光明，
give him the wild man for a brother,
给他一个野蛮的兄弟，
and the wild Montana sky.
和蒙大拿的狂野天空。
Pat Hart helping me out there.
Pat Hart在那里帮助我。
Where the walker runs down through the Carson Valley plain,
在沃克尔河穿越卡森谷平原，
there lived a maiden, Darcy Farrell was her name,
住着一个少女，达西·法雷尔是她的名字，
the daughter of old Undie, Fair One Sheep,
是老安迪的女儿，公平的羊，
the sweetest flower that bloomed o'er the range.
是山脉中开放的最甜美的花朵。
Her voice was as sweet as the sugar candy,
她的声音像糖果一样甜美，
her touch was as soft as a bed of goose down,
她的触感像一床鹅绒一样柔软，
her eyes shone bright like the pretty lights.
她的眼睛闪烁着明亮的光芒。
The shining night out of Yarrington town,
她的美丽照亮了亚灵顿镇的夜晚，
she was corded by young land to near,
年轻的兰德向她求爱，
a find that was he as I am to hear.
这是一个他希望的机会，就像我听到的一样。
He gave her silver rings and they seemed faint,
他送给她银戒指，它们看起来如此美丽，
she promised to wear them before the snows came that year,
她答应会在那年的雪来临之前戴上它们，
but her pony did stumble, but she did fall,
但她的小马绊倒了，她摔倒了，
her dye in touch the hearts of us one and all.
她的去世触动了我们所有人的心。
Young Vandy in his pain put a bullet through his brain,
年轻的范迪在痛苦中将子弹射入了脑中，
we buried them together as the snows began to fall.
我们将他们一起埋葬，当雪开始飘落时。
They sang of Darcy Farrell where the truckie runs through,
他们唱着达西·法雷尔的歌，当特拉基河流过时，
they sang of her beauty in the genius city too.
他们在城市里也唱着她的美丽。
At the skis are down to her name they drink around,
他们举杯向她的名字干杯，
too young Vandy whose love was true.
为年轻的范迪，他的爱是真挚的。
I've been late to thinking about my life's time,
我开始思考我的一生，
all the things I've done, how it's been,
我所做的一切，以及它是如何的，
I can't help believing in my own mind,
我不禁相信自己的内心，
I know I'm gonna hate to see it again.
我知道我会不愿再见到它。
I've seen a lot of sunshine slept out in the rain,
我见过很多阳光，也在雨中入睡，
spends a night or two all on my own.
有几个夜晚独自一人。
I've known my ladies pleasures, had myself some friends,
我享受了女士的快乐，结交了一些朋友，
spent a night or two in my own home.
在我自己的家中度过了一两个夜晚。
I have to say it now, it's been a good life all along,
我不得不说，这一路走来，这是一段美好的生活，
it's really fine to have a chance to hang around,
真的很好能有机会继续生活下去。
and lie there by the fire and watch the evening tire,
躺在火边，看夜晚慢慢变得疲倦，
while all my friends and my old lady sit and pass a pipe around.
当我的朋友和我的老伴一起坐着，传递着一支烟斗。
Talk of poems and prayers and promises and things that we believe in,
谈论诗歌、祈祷、诺言和我们相信的事物，
how sweet it is to love someone, how right it is to care,
爱某人是多么甜蜜，关心某人是多么正确，
how long it's been since yesterday,
从昨天以来多长时间了，
what about tomorrow, what about our dreams,
明天怎么样，我们的梦想呢，
and all the memories we share.
以及我们分享的所有回忆。
The days they pass so quickly now, the nights they seldom long,
现在日子过得如此迅速，夜晚很少很长，
the time around me whispers when it's cold,
当寒冷时，时间在我周围低语，
the changes somehow frighten me, still I have to smile,
变化总是让我感到害怕，但我还是得微笑，
it turns me on to think of road at home.
想着回家的路让我兴奋。
Though my life's been but to me there's still so much to do,
尽管我的生活已经过去，但对我来说还有很多事情要做，
so many things my mind is never known.
我的心里还有很多事情我从未知道。
I'd like to raise a family, I'd like to sail away,
我想要养育一个家庭，我想要出海，
and dance across the mountains on a boat, yes I know,
在一艘船上穿越山脉，是的，我知道，
I have to say now it's been a good life all along,
我不得不说，这一路走来，这是一段美好的生活，
it's really fine to have a chance to hang around,
真的很好能有机会继续生活下去，
and lie there by the fire and watch the evening tire,
躺在火边，看夜晚慢慢变得疲倦，
while all my friends and my old baby sit and watch the sun go down.
而我的朋友和我的老伴坐在那里，看太阳落山。
And talk of poems and prayers and promises and things that we believe in,
并谈论诗歌、祈祷、诺言和我们相信的事物，
how sweet it is to love someone, how right it is to care,
爱某人是多么甜蜜，关心某人是多么正确，
how long it's been since yesterday, what about tomorrow,
从昨天以来多长时间了，明天怎么样，
what about our dreams and all the memories we share?
我们的梦想和我们分享的所有回忆呢？
I wish she was at home, she's mad because the baby just ain't treating her right,
我希望她在家，她生气是因为宝宝对她不好，
so afraid of being alone, said she's heard some stories,
害怕独自一人，她听到了一些故事，
he's been running around, said somehow she knows it's all true,
他到处乱跑，她总觉得这都是真的，
she said a break in the heart can make a terrible sound,
她说，心碎会发出可怕的声音，
said she just don't know what to do, think about it that time,
她说她不知道该怎么办，想到那个时候，
can't give much worse, think about a hard life, take it to the wall,
不能再糟糕了，想一想艰难的生活，把它扛到墙上，
this won't be the last time, sure ain't the first,
这不会是最后一次，肯定不是第一次，
think here they are, the harder they fall.
想想吧，他们越困难，摔得越重。
You might say she's called between a rock and a hard place,
你可能会说她被夹在一块石头和一个困境之间，
you might think she just can't win, sound just can't recover from a slap in her face,
你可能会认为她无法取胜，声音无法从一巴掌中恢复，
some could just write up, start all over again,
有些人只是重新开始，
oh, like about a bad time, can't give much worse,
哦，就像糟糕的时光，不能再糟糕了，
think about a hard life and take it to the wall,
想一想艰难的生活，把它扛到墙上，
this won't be the last time, sure ain't the first,
这不会是最后一次，肯定不是第一次，
think here they are, the harder they fall.
想想吧，他们越困难，摔得越重。
Take it that time, can't give much worse,
那时请忍受，不能再糟糕了，
think about a hard life and take it to the wall,
想一想艰难的生活，把它扛到墙上，
this won't be the last time, sure ain't the first,
这不会是最后一次，肯定不是第一次，
think here they are, the harder they fall.
想想吧，他们越困难，摔得越重。
Aspen Colorado on a Saturday night,
在科罗拉多州阿斯彭的一个周六晚上，
just there was she was at home,
她就在那里，她在家，
she's mad because maybe ain't treating her right,
她生气是因为也许对她不好，
but so afraid of being alone,
但害怕独自一人，
she's so afraid of being alone,
她非常害怕独自一人，
nobody wants to be alone no more,
没有人想再独自一人了，
I don't want to sleep alone no more.
我不想再独自入睡了。
Who'd have thought that time,
谁会想到那个时候，
Johnny Denver doing rock and roll.
约翰尼·丹佛（John Denver）演绎摇滚乐。
Five hundred'll buy you a stack,
五百可以给你一叠筹码，
bet it all on the red of the black and you lose,
把它全押在红色或黑色上，结果你输了，
bet on the blues,
下注在蓝调上，
you tell me you are a gamblin' man,
你告诉我你是个赌徒，
try to beat the house if you can't, you lose,
试着战胜庄家，如果做不到，你就输了，
bet on the blues,
下注在蓝调上，
if you're looking to get an inside slant,
如果你想获得内部线索，
if you're looking for something so good,
如果你在寻找一些如此美好，
you can't refuse,
你无法拒绝，
bet on the blues,
下注在蓝调上，
find a man who thinks he's over the hump,
找个人以为他已度过难关，
and I'm here to tell you he's a kind of a chunk you can use,
我在这里告诉你，他是你可以利用的一种人，
bet on the blues,
下注在蓝调上，
Lucky ol' son is shining day,
幸运的儿子是阳光明媚的一天，
even money says you'll be payin' some dues,
就算钱说你将付出一些代价，
bet on the blues,
下注在蓝调上，
you say you found your lady fair,
你说你找到了你的女士，
eight to five says she's wearin' her travelin' shoes,
八比五说她穿着旅行鞋，
bet on the blues,
下注在蓝调上，
five hundred'll buy you a stack,
五百可以给你一叠筹码，
bet it on the red or the black and you lose,
把它全押在红色或黑色上，结果你输了，
bet on the blues,
下注在蓝调上，
if you're looking to get an inside slant,
如果你想获得内部线索，
if you're looking for something so good,
如果你在寻找一些如此美好，
you can't refuse,
你无法拒绝，
bet on the blues,
下注在蓝调上，
bet on the blues.
下注在蓝调上。
This is what it's like falling out of love,
这就是爱情消失的滋味，
this is the way you lose your very best friend,
这是你失去最好的朋友的方式，
this is how it feels when it's all over,
这是结束时的感觉，
this is just the way true love is.
这就是真爱的方式。
First of all, there's no one you can talk to,
首先，没有人可以和你交谈，
when there is, they just don't seem to hear,
即使有人，他们似乎也听不见，
words don't seem to matter much anyway,
话语似乎也没有多大意义，
they can't describe the pain,
他们无法描述这种痛苦，
they can't explain the fear,
他们无法解释这种恐惧，
and then the nights grow cold and hard to live through,
然后夜晚变得寒冷而难以度过，
and still you hate to see the morning come,
而你仍然不愿看到早晨到来，
but somehow tomorrow doesn't matter much anymore,
但不知何故，明天不再那么重要，
the future holds no promise,
未来没有承诺，
your life's already done,
你的生活已经结束，
this is what it's like falling out of love,
这就是爱情消失的滋味，
this is the way you lose your very best friend,
这是你失去最好的朋友的方式，
this is how it feels when it's all over,
这是结束时的感觉，
this is just the way true love is.
这就是真爱的方式。
Then you find your heart no longer flutters,
然后你发现你的心再也不会跳动，
and you no longer look through a lover's eyes,
你再也不会以恋人的眼光看待事物，
cause what's to see when the world comes down around you,
因为当世界在你周围崩塌时，还能看到什么，
you simply can't believe it,
你简直无法相信，
but it comes as no surprise,
但这一点也不令人惊讶，
cause this is what it's like falling out of love,
因为这就是爱情消失的滋味，
this is the way you lose your very best friend,
这是你失去最好的朋友的方式，
this is how it feels when it's all over,
这是结束时的感觉，
this is just the way true love is,
这就是真爱的方式。
What's the sense of failure, it's such an incredible loss,
失败的意义是什么，它是如此难以置信的损失，
it's all the things you'll never do,
它是所有你永远不会做的事情，
and all the dreams I will never come true,
和所有我永远无法实现的梦想，
this is what it's like falling out of love,
这就是爱情消失的滋味，
this is the way you lose your very best friend,
这是你失去最好的朋友的方式，
this is how it feels when it's all over,
这是结束时的感觉，
this is just the way true love is,
这就是真爱的方式，
oh this is just the way true love is,
哦，这就是真爱的方式，
and I don't believe the true love ever is.
而且我不相信真爱会永远存在。
Oh no, oh no, oh no, no, no, no.
哦不，哦不，哦不，不，不，不。
I mean the question I'm most asked about the environment is,
我的意思是，有关环境，我最经常被问到的问题是，
the problems are so big, what can I do?
问题如此庞大，我能做什么？
And I remind people, well you don't have to do it all,
我提醒人们，你不必做所有事情，
but there is something that you can do,
但有一些事情你可以做，
and it can be easy, it doesn't have to be a great sacrifice,
而且它可以很容易，不必牺牲很大，
as I say, if it comes out of your own heart and spirit,
就像我说的，如果它源自你自己的内心和精神，
your own inclinations, it's a thing that's easy to do,
你自己的倾向，这是一件容易做的事，
so you do the thing that you can do,
所以你做你可以做的事，
that is an expression of who you are,
这是对你自己的表达，
and an expression of your sense of relationship to nature,
以及你与大自然的关系感，
to the environment.
对环境的关系。
You do the thing that you can do, I'll do the thing that I can do,
你做你能做的事，我做我能做的事，
and we'll try to get these other people to do what they can do with these people,
然后我们会努力让其他人和这些人一起做他们能做的事，
and we can save ourselves.
这样我们可以拯救自己。
The questions I know, to be part of the movement,
我知道的问题，是要成为这个运动的一部分，
part of the growing, part of beginning to understand.
成长的一部分，开始理解的一部分。
I can live so the place you've been to,
我可以生活在你曾经去过的地方，
think that you've shown us the stories you tell.
想象着你向我们展示的故事。
I can live so I sing to your spirit,
我可以生活，唱给你的精神听，
the man who I've served so long and so well,
我为之服务了如此之久的人。
for the lady, for the lady, for the lady, for the lady, for the lady.
为了这位女士，为了这位女士，为了这位女士，为了这位女士，为了这位女士。
I could often do guides you, you bring us beside you,
我可以经常引导你，你带领我们在你身边，
to light up the darkness, to show us the way.
照亮黑暗，为我们指引道路。
Although we are strangers in your silent world,
尽管我们是你无声世界中的陌生人，
to live on the land we must learn from the sea,
要生活在陆地上，我们必须向大海学习，
to be true as the tide, and free as the winds,
像潮汐一样真实，像风一样自由，
while joyful and loving and letting it be.
同时充满喜悦和爱，顺其自然。
I can live so the place you've been to,
我可以生活在你曾经去过的地方，
think that you've shown us the stories you tell.
想象着你向我们展示的故事。
I can live so I sing to your spirit,
我可以生活，唱给你的精神听，
the man who I've served so long and so well.
那个我已经侍奉了如此之久并做得很好的人。
I can live so the place you've been to,
我可以生活在你曾经去过的地方，
think that you've shown us the stories you tell.
想象着你向我们展示的故事。
I can live so I sing to your spirit,
我可以生活，唱给你的精神听，
the man who I've served so long and so well,
那个我已经侍奉了如此之久并做得很好的人，
for the lady, for the lady, for the lady, for the lady.
为了这位女士，为了这位女士，为了这位女士，为了这位女士。
For the lady, for the lady, for the lady, for the lady, for the lady.
为了这位女士，为了这位女士，为了这位女士，为了这位女士，为了这位女士。
Resentment and Regret
怨恨和后悔
Resentment to say that as air is to the bird,
怨恨就像鸟儿的空气一样，
as water is to a fish, so is resentment and regret to humankind.
就像水对鱼一样，怨恨和后悔对人类来说。
And in so much of what's going on in the world today,
而在当今世界的许多事情中，
there is the opportunity for both on some sides
在某些方面，双方都有机会
and enormous resentment that people's lives have to change
和巨大的怨恨，因为人们的生活必须改变
or jobs have to change because of environmental issues.
或者因环境问题而必须改变工作。
On the other side of it is the potential for an enormous amount of regret.
另一方面，潜在的巨大后悔可能性。
I think of the people in lumber industry up in the Northwest
我想到西北地区的木材行业人员
who are concerned about losing their jobs and changing a lifestyle.
担心失去工作和改变生活方式。
And at the same time, I wonder how many of them recognize
与此同时，我不禁想知道他们中有多少人意识到
that the streams are so siltified from runoff,
溪流因径流而变得泥沙淤积，
from where clear cutting has been taking place,
从伐木清理地点发生的地方，
that the salmon are no longer coming in, that the fishing is down.
以至于鲑鱼不再涌入，钓鱼减少。
And see, I have a thought, I want with all of my heart
我明白，我全心全意想
to be able to go fishing with my grandkids.
能够和我的孙子孙女一起钓鱼。
And I want to go show them coral reefs in the ocean.
我想带他们去海洋中展示珊瑚礁。
I remember the day I first took my kids snorkeling.
我记得第一次带孩子们浮潜的那一天。
I remember the day, the first day that I went fishing with my son, Zach.
我记得第一天和我儿子扎克一起钓鱼的那一天。
And I think all people have that kind of feeling in their hearts.
我认为所有人都有这种感觉。
And how much would there be to regret if we destroyed that opportunity for ourselves?
如果我们摧毁了自己的这一机会，会有多少后悔？
So it's something I think that we have to be mindful of
因此，我认为这是我们必须警惕的事情
as we make the decisions that have to do with our lives
当我们做出与我们的生活有关的决策时
and how we live our lives and what we want out of our lives.
以及我们如何过我们的生活和我们对生活的期望。
There is a river that runs from the mountains
有一条从山上流过的河
that one river is all rivers.
那条河就是所有的河流。
All rivers are that one.
所有河流都是这一条。
There is a tree that stands in the forest
有一棵树矗立在森林中
that one tree is all forests.
那棵树就是所有的森林。
All trees are that one.
所有树木都是那一棵。
There is a flower that blooms in the desert
有一朵花在沙漠中绽放
that one blossom is all flowers.
那朵花就是所有的花。
All flowers are that one.
所有的花都是那一朵。
There is a bird that sings in the jungle
有一只鸟在丛林中歌唱
that one song is all music.
那首歌就是所有的音乐。
All songs are that one.
所有的歌曲都是那一首。
It is a song of life.
这是一首关于生命的歌曲。
It is a flower of faith.
这是一朵信仰之花。
It is a tree of temptation.
这是一棵引诱之树。
It is a river of no regrets.
这是一条没有后悔的河流。
There is a child that cries in the ghetto
贫民区有一个哭泣的孩子
that one child is all of our children.
那一个孩子代表着我们所有的孩子。
All of our children are that one.
我们所有的孩子都是那一个。
There is a vision that shines in the darkness
在黑暗中闪耀的有一个愿景
that one vision is all of our dreams.
那一个愿景代表着我们所有的梦想。
All of our dreams are that one.
我们所有的梦想都是那一个。
It is a vision of heaven.
这是一个天堂的愿景。
It is a child of promise.
这是一个充满希望的孩子。
It is a tree of temptation.
这是一棵引诱之树。
It is a river of no regrets.
这是一条没有后悔的河流。
It is a tree of temptation.
这是一棵引诱之树。
Let this be a voice for the mountains.
让这成为山脉的声音。
Let this be a voice for the rivers.
让这成为河流的声音。
Let this be a voice for the forests.
让这成为森林的声音。
Let this be a voice for the flower.
让这成为花朵的声音。
Let this be a voice for the desert.
让这成为沙漠的声音。
Let this be a voice for the ocean.
让这成为海洋的声音。
Let this be a voice for the children.
让这成为儿童的声音。
Let this be a voice for the dreamers.
让这成为梦想家的声音。
Where
在哪里
I think that I would most like to be remembered for the fact that I stood up for what I believe
我认为最希望被记住的是我为自己的信仰站出来
in, that I spoke for it, I sang for it, I worked for the things that I believe in in
我说出来，我为之歌唱，我为我相信的事情而努力
the world.
在这个世界中。
I guess the thing that I feel best about, I'm not sure that I can say that it's what
我想我感到最自豪的事情，我不确定我能不能说这是我最喜欢自己的事情
I like most about myself, I don't think of those terms, but my music, the songs, the
我不用那种词汇思考，但我的音乐，歌曲，歌曲
songs that I've written, and the gifts that I have, that's why it's hard to say that
我写的歌曲，以及我所拥有的礼物，这就是为什么很难说
I like this best about myself, I really don't own this, it is a gift and I'm very grateful
我最喜欢自己的事情，我真的不拥有这一切，这是一份礼物，我非常感激
for it.
对此非常感激。
All my bags are packed, I'm ready to go, I'm standing here outside your door, I hate to
我的行李已经打包好，我已经准备好，我站在你的门外，我不愿意
wake you up to say goodbye, but the dawn is breaking, it's early morning, the taxis
叫醒你告别，但黎明即将到来，早晨，出租车
are coming, he's blown his horn, and already I'm so lonesome I could die, so kiss me and
正在来，他吹响了喇叭，我已经非常寂寞，以至于我可能会死，所以亲吻我
smile for me, tell me that you'll wait for me, hold me like you'll never let me go,
为我微笑，告诉我你会等我，紧紧拥抱我，不会放手，
cause I'm leaving on a jet plane, don't know when I'll be back again, oh baby I hate
因为我要搭乘飞机离开，不知道什么时候会回来，哦，宝贝，我不愿意离开。
to go.
去了。
There's so many times I've let you down, so many times I've played around, I tell you
有太多次我让你失望，有太多次我胡闹，我告诉你
now, they don't mean a thing, every place I go I'll think of you, every song I sing
现在，它们一点意义都没有，我走到哪里都会想着你，我唱的每首歌
I'll sing for you, when I come back I'll bring your wedding ring, so kiss me and smile for
我会为你唱，当我回来时我会带上你的结婚戒指，所以亲吻我，为我微笑
me, tell me that you'll wait for me, hold me like you'll never let me go, cause I'm
为我微笑，告诉我你会等我，紧紧拥抱我，不会放手，因为我
leaving on a jet plane, don't know when I'll be back again, oh baby I hate to go.
搭乘飞机离开，不知道什么时候会回来，哦，宝贝，我不愿意离开。
Now the time has come to leave you, one more time, let me kiss you and close your eyes,
现在是离开你的时候了，再一次，让我吻你，闭上你的眼睛，
I'll be on my way, dream about the days to come, when I won't have to leave alone, about
我要上路了，梦想着未来的日子，当我不再孤单地离开时，关于
the times I won't have to say, kiss me and smile for me, tell me that you'll wait for
我不再说出的时候，亲吻我，为我微笑，告诉我你会等我，
me, hold me like you'll never let me go, cause I'm leaving on a jet plane, don't know when
紧紧拥抱我，不会放手，因为我要搭乘飞机离开，不知道什么时候会回来，
I'll be back again, oh baby I hate to go, I'm leaving on a jet plane, don't know when I'll
我会再回来的，哦，宝贝，我讨厌离开，我搭乘喷气飞机离开，不知道何时会回来，
be back again, oh baby I hate to go.
再次回来，哦，宝贝，我讨厌离开。
It's five o'clock this morning and the sun is on the way, crossing on the windowpane,
早上五点钟，太阳已经升起，穿过窗户玻璃，
the sorrow in your eyes, the stars are fading quietly, the night is nearly gone, so you
你眼中的忧伤，星星悄悄地褪去，夜幕已近尾声，所以你
turn away from me, tears begin to come, it's goodbye again, I'm sorry to believe in you,
背对着我，泪水开始流淌，又是告别，对不起，我对你的信仰感到抱歉，
goodbye again, cause if you didn't know it's goodbye again, and I wish you could tell me,
再次告别，因为如果你不知道，这又是告别，我希望你能告诉我，
why do we always fight when I have to go, it seems a shame to leave you now, you lay so soft and warm,
为什么每次我不得不离开时我们总是争吵，现在离开你似乎很可惜，你躺得那么温柔而温暖，
I long to lay me down again, and hold you in my arms, I long to kiss the tears away, give you back your smile,
我渴望再次躺下，将你拥入怀中，我渴望亲吻你的泪水，还你的微笑，
but other voices beckon me, before a little while, it's goodbye again, I'm sorry to believe in you, goodbye again,
但其他声音在召唤我，再过一会儿，又是告别，对不起，我对你的信仰感到抱歉，再次告别，
cause if you didn't know it's goodbye again, and I wish you could tell me, why do we always fight when I have to go,
因为如果你不知道，这又是告别，我希望你能告诉我，为什么每次我不得不离开时我们总是争吵，
I have to go and see some friends of mine, some that I don't know, some who aren't familiar with my name,
我不得不去看看我的一些朋友，有些我不认识，有些不熟悉我的名字，
it's something that's inside of me, not hard to understand, it's just anyone who'll listen to me sing,
这是我内心的一部分，不难理解，只要有人愿意听我唱歌，
if your hours are empty now, who am I to blame, do you think if I were always here, our love would be the same,
如果你的时光现在是空虚的，我怪谁呢，你认为如果我一直在这里，我们的爱会是一样的吗，
and as it is the time we have, it's worth the time alone, lying by your side, the greatest peace I've ever known, goodbye again,
现在我们所拥有的时间就是孤独的时间，躺在你的身边，是我所知道的最大的平静，再次告别，
I'm sorry to believe in you, goodbye again, cause if you didn't know it's goodbye again,
对不起，我对你的信仰感到抱歉，再次告别，
and I wish you could tell me, why do we always fight when I have to go,
我希望你能告诉我，为什么每次我不得不离开时我们总是争吵，
Thank you.
谢谢。